Yiming Zhu

Lower Mainland (431)887-1218 yzhu97@my.bcit.ca

Profile

With professional experience as a laboratory assistant with Bayer Canada in Winnipeg, where I collaborated effectively with a team to support daily laboratory operations, I have demonstrated strong teamwork and technical skills. In China, I have over a decade of experience in probiotic powder sales and service, managing sales targets and leading teams to drive business success. I am new to programming, but I have contributed to open source programs with my limited knowledge of C. I am seeking a job that is both interesting and challenging, where I can leverage my diverse expertise and passion for contributing in programming.

Tech Skills

- JavaScript, Node.js
- C programming, Java
- Linux, Windows

- React, Vite, Ejs, jQuery
- Relational Database and SQL
- MangoDB, Firebase, Firestore

Personal Projects

Portfolio / https://yimingzhu.netlify.app

July.2024

Personal portfolio

- Display my projects, skills, and contact form
- Provide resume for downloading
- Tech used: React, Vite, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

hash.c / https://github.com/Nivedpv2004/C-PROGRAMING

July.2024

Open source contributor

• Create a "hash.c" program (hash table in C) for the C-Programming project

Academic Projects

Document / https://github.com/Donut11one/2800-202410-BBY02

Apr- May 2024

Projects 2, BCIT

- Worked with a team of 5 using the Agile development process and Scrum framework
- Developed an app that can let user create and upload their NFTs to blockchain
- Did the login and account creation part for the website
- Developed the help page and let user give feedback
- Tech I used: Tailwind CSS, React, Dom, Bootstrap, Node.js, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Firebase, Firestore

Roove / https://github.com/tommytty/1800 202410 BBY18

Jan- Apr 2024

Projects 1, BCIT

- Worked with a team of 3 using Agile development process
- Developed an app that let user find their preferred roommates to rent together
- Tech used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Firebase, Firestore

Experience

Laboratory Assistant / BAYER CROP SCIENCE, WINNIPEG

Feb-Oct 2022

- Worked with the whole opreation team to daily care the haploid canola plants
- Did morning stand up meeting every day

- Did the daily tasks such as seeding, trimming, crossing, harvesting, watering ...
- Recorded experimental data for later analysis
- Volunteered to help other departments of the company (in another city)

Sales Manager / WUXI BAIFUDE BIOTECH COMPANY, WUXI

- Founded Wuxi BAIFUDE Company
- Developed many brand customers which are still cooperating with the company
- Maintain customer relationship and achieve sales targets
- Communicate with customers about product improvement and after sales issues

Sales Team Leader / BioGrowing Co., LTD., Shanghai

Oct 2010 – Mar 2013

Apr 2013 - Mar 2019

- Be responsible for probiotic sales at dairy and functional foods in East China Region
- Establish and manage new agriculture probiotic project
- Lead a team of five members to achieve sales targets, conduct several research projects

Project Researcher / ZTE Agribusiness Co., LTD, Beijing & Overseas

Jun 2008 - Mar 2010

- Had been trained in palm plantation for six months and win the outstanding award
- Surveyed soil composition at East Kalimantan and write research reports
- Worked on the feasibility study of agribusiness investment in Sudan, Africa
- Served as a technical manager of the fuel ethanol project at Inner Mongolia

Education

Computer System Technology diploma/

British Columbia Institute of Technology, BC, Canada on going

Business Management Certification (postgraduate program) /

Manitoba Institute of Trades and Technology, Winnipeg Aug 2021

Master of Science(Major in Microbiology) /

South China University of Tropical Agriculture, Haikou, China Jul 2007

Bachelor of Engineering(Major in Food Science and Engineering) /

South China University of Tropical Agriculture, Danzhou, China Jul 2004